<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>giacomocavalieri.me posts feed</title><link>https://giacomocavalieri.me</link><description>All the posts from my personal blog about programming.</description><language>en</language><pubDate>30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><item><title>Goodbye, 2025</title><link>https://giacomocavalieri.me/posts/goodbye-2025.html</link><description>New year, new me, and new personal website! Time to reflect on 2025</description><author>giacomo.cavalieri@icloud.com</author><pubDate>30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fixing my gripes with GitHub using Gleam and a Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://giacomocavalieri.me/posts/fixing-my-gripes-with-github-using-gleam-and-a-raspberry-pi.html</link><description>As a programmer there&#39;s no greater joy than trying to code my way out of little daily annoyances. Lately I&#39;ve been annoyed by GitHub&#39;s UI and I set up to fix this using Gleam and a little Raspberry Pi Zero.</description><author>giacomo.cavalieri@icloud.com</author><pubDate>08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>/uses</title><link>https://giacomocavalieri.me/posts/uses.html</link><description>Things I use, from hardware, to note taking, and of course software!</description><author>giacomo.cavalieri@icloud.com</author><pubDate>15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Goodbye, 2024</title><link>https://giacomocavalieri.me/posts/goodbye-2024.html</link><description>I&#39;m not great at doing end-of-year introspection; but this has been such a fun year and I wanted to share a bit of what I did on the internet</description><author>giacomo.cavalieri@icloud.com</author><pubDate>30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A new Gleam feature I love</title><link>https://giacomocavalieri.me/posts/a-new-gleam-feature-i-love.html</link><description>A new Gleam release is right around the corner and it will come with a new feature I absolutely love:  label shorthands.  It might not be as flashy as other features but I wanted to implement it for the longest time and think it will really help me write better code. Here&#39;s what it&#39;s all about.</description><author>giacomo.cavalieri@icloud.com</author><pubDate>26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What if best practices were the norm?</title><link>https://giacomocavalieri.me/posts/what-if-best-practices-were-the-norm.html</link><description>During my second year of university I followed a course dedicated to object-oriented programming and quickly fell in love with Java. My honeymoon phase with it is long over and I&#39;ve come to dislike a lot of the ceremonies and self-imposed restrictions that can come with good object-oriented code. So  what if the best practices I&#39;m forcing myself to follow were easier to adopt and put into practice?</description><author>giacomo.cavalieri@icloud.com</author><pubDate>26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Look! I made this with Gleam</title><link>https://giacomocavalieri.me/posts/look-i-made-this-with-gleam.html</link><description>I love functional programming and getting caught in rabbit holes; the thing I love most, though, is sharing what I learn with my friends. What better way to pester even more people than setting up a personal blog?</description><author>giacomo.cavalieri@icloud.com</author><pubDate>18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>